Experience it. Enjoy it. Just don't fall for it.
Almost Famous is a drama, music film directed by Cameron Crowe.
In 1973, 15-year-old William Miller's unabashed love of music and aspiration to become a rock journalist lands him an
assignment from Rolling Stone magazine to interview and tour with the up-and-coming band, Stillwater.
Russell Hammond, played by Billy Crudup.
Elaine Miller, played by Frances McDormand.
Penny Lane, played by Kate Hudson.
Jeff Bebe, played by Jason Lee.
William Miller, played by Patrick Fugit.
Anita Miller, played by Zooey Deschanel.
Almost Famous is a 2000 American comedy drama film written and directed by Cameron Crowe, starring
Billy Crudup, Frances McDormand, Kate Hudson, Patrick Fugit, and Philip Seymour Hoffman.
It tells the story of a teenage journalist, played by Fugit, writing for Rolling Stone magazine in the early 1970s,
touring with the fictitious rock band Stillwater, and writing his first cover story on the band.
The film is semi-autobiographical, based on Crowe's
experiences as a teenage writer for Rolling Stone.
The film performed poorly in theaters, grossing $47.4
million against a $60 million budget.
It was widely acclaimed by critics and earned four Academy Award
nominations, including a win for Best Original Screenplay.
It also won the 2001 Grammy Award for Best Compilation Soundtrack Album
for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media.
Roger Ebert hailed it as the best film of the year
and the ninth-best film of the 2000s.
The film also won two Golden Globe Awards, one for Best Motion Picture – Musical or
Comedy and another for Best Supporting Actress – Motion Picture for Hudson.
The film is regarded by some as a cult classic and in a 2016 international poll conducted by the  BBC, Almost Famous was ranked the
79th-greatest film since 2000, while it was ranked as the 47th-best film of the 21st century in a 2025 poll by The New York Times.
In a Hollywood Reporter 2014 list voted on by "studio chiefs, Oscar winners and TV
royalty", Almost Famous was ranked the 71st-greatest film of all time.
A stage musical adaptation of the film opened on Broadway in November 2022.
The film explores themes of hotel room, concert, rock
'n' roll, stewardess, drug addiction.
The tone is emotional.